# **Toh Hong Xiang**

Self-driven and dependable web developer with 1 year experience, familiar in conducting analysis to pinpoint effective solutions for various end-users. Quick in adapting unfamiliar technologies to deliver impactful products ahead of deadlines. Focused on creating an intuitive, problem-free user experience.

Singapore +65 9431 7592 tohhongxiang@gmail.com

### **EXPERIENCE**

# Industrial Electronics Pte Ltd, Software Developer

Dec 2019 - July 2020

- Designed and implemented new features to for an e-commerce web application to track and trade warehouse stocks
- Developed a Drag-&-Drop template builder for websites
- Implemented smooth UI/UX, delivering consistent results ahead of schedule
- Demonstrated high levels of initiative by spotting potential bugs ahead of time, constant code refactoring

# Singapore Armed Forces, Admin Support Assistant

Aug 2019 - Oct 2019

- Built a small web application to help the management of large complicated menus within SAF Cookhouses
- Implemented website using MongoDB, Express, React and Node
- Focused on clear and intuitive user interfaces to cater to the technologically unfamiliar market
- Significantly lowered error rates by 80%, and improved efficiency by 20%
- Demo and Code

### **EDUCATION**

# Nanyang Technological University, Singapore

July 2020 - July 2024

Currently studying for a Bachelor of Computer Science

# Anderson Junior College, Singapore

Jan 2016 - Dec 2017

H2 Physics, H2 Math, H2 Chemistry and H1 Economics, with an additional H3 Math. Scored 90 rank points in GCE 'A' Levels 2018

### LINKS

### **Portfolio**

https://tohhongxiang123.gi thub.io/Portfolio/

#### Github

https://github.com/tohhongxiang123

#### LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/i n/toh-hong-xiang-3155111 8b/

## **SKILLS**

## Front-End

- HTML, CSS, JS
- React (With redux)
- React Native
- Vue
- Bootstrap
- SCSS
- jQuery

### Back-End

- Node
- Typescript
- Express
- MongoDB
- PostgreSQL
- GraphQL/REST
- TypeORM

### Miscellaneous

- Version Control (Git)
- Github Actions (CI/CD)
- Photoshop/Figma
- Heroku
- Python

# **FEATURED PROJECTS**

# "Stumblr" Social Media Website — Tumblr Clone

- Uses PostgreSQL, Node, Express, React
- Tumblr Clone, features basic CRUD and user authentication
- Demo and Code

# Gallereddit — Gallery Visualizer for Reddit ■ Uses React and Express

- Data pulled using Reddit and Imgur API
- Features OAuth2 to connect web application to reddit users
- Demo and Code